<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advanced Interaction with Drawings on Educational material for LSU Programming Digital Media</title>
    <link>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advanced Interaction with Drawings on Educational material for LSU Programming Digital Media</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/2_graphics/2_paintapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Boundaries of a Shape</title>
      <link>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/1_lesson_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/1_lesson_1/</guid>
      <description>In your projects, you&amp;rsquo;ll often want to have interactive mouse events tied to specific shapes or drawings. It&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that any shape or object drawn on the canvas can&amp;rsquo;t simply be referred to by name, since p5.js has no way of knowing the difference between a green triangle or a pink square. In order to determine whether or not a user has clicked on a 2D object, we have to use conditional statements to measure whether or not the mouse click occurred within the boundaries of that object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested Conditionals &amp; Complex Boundary Measurement</title>
      <link>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/2_lesson_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/2_lesson_2/</guid>
      <description>In our last lesson, you may have noticed that our conditional tests looked a little repetitive. When measuring shapes that have multiple boundaries on the same X or Y coordinate, we can save ourselves the hassle of repeating portions of a test by using Nested Conditionals. Lets take a look at a diagram demonstrating the logic of a Nested Conditional to refresh our memories from Unit 1:
graph TD H{Outer Test}-.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphics Assignment # 2 - Paint App</title>
      <link>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/3_lesson_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2_graphics/2_paintapp/3_lesson_3/</guid>
      <description>Below is an example of the Paint app assignment. Play around with it and notice the following things that are required for your project:
 Number and location of color squares What happens when you clock on the color squares What happens when you click and drag the mouse What happens when you click on the white square  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>